ERIK SANNE

10/03/1998 | 253 Dalry Rd, Edinburgh EH112JQ, United Kingdom | 07566234274 | erik@eriksanne.com | www.eriksanne.com

Profile

Highly skilled and motivated Software Engineering undergraduate, with over one year of experience in professional software development. Solid knowledge of the design, development and testing of computer software, with innovative problem-solving skills and proven attention to detail. Analytical with excellent critical reasoning, with a commitment to deliver quality performance and maintain professional excellence.

Skills

Programming languages

Java and Spring Boot JavaScript Python C# C, C++ SOL

Soft skills

English Fluent
German Native
Numerical skills
Stakeholder Engagement
Scrum and Waterfall
Methodologies

Work experience

Business Analyst Intern 06/2019 - 08/2019

MarketAxess, London, United Kingdom

- Production of high-level and detailed business specifications for enhancements on the trading system
- Participation in Scrum as Product Owner, liaising with internal stakeholders such as Product Managers to discuss client needs, prioritizing enhancements such as bug fixes for software developers
- Creating financial models to better enable the sales team

Industrial Placement Application Development 06/2018 – 05/2019

Morgan Stanley, Glasgow, United Kingdom

- Performance tuned a component within a market-leading trading system, increasing performance 70-80x which resolved associated production problems and relieving pressure on the operations team
- Led the migration and enhancement of a software feature from Perl scripts to a new Java Spring Boot system, increasing revenue and retention of clients
- Build a new Java Spring Boot backend application with RESTful API and Freemarker templating, enabling
 developers across the firm to start new projects with better project templates which reduced set up
 times and increased productivity

Product Specialist (Fraud Dept) 05/2017 - 05/2018

Sykes Global Services, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

- Monitoring of customer transactions to identify suspicious activity including possible fraud
- Analysed historical data to point out inefficiencies to the stakeholder, allowing the team to spend more time on complicated transactions

Education

BEng (Hons) Software Engineering 09/2016 - present

Edinburgh Napier University, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

 Subjects include the analysis, design, development, testing, evaluation, and modification of reliable, maintainable and high-quality software including real-time, mobile and large-scale enterprise systems.

Social Media







ersanne